<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://bearzsh.github.io/blog</id>
    <title>Bearz.sh Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-06-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://bearzsh.github.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Bearz.sh Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://bearzsh.github.io/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Initial Post]]></title>
        <id>https://bearzsh.github.io/blog/initial-post</id>
        <link href="https://bearzsh.github.io/blog/initial-post"/>
        <updated>2023-06-02T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Bearz.sh is live.  A progressive launch for a documentation hub and blog around]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="language-bash codeBlockContainer_Ckt0 theme-code-block" style="--prism-color:#F8F8F2;--prism-background-color:#282A36"><div class="codeBlockContent_biex"><pre tabindex="0" class="prism-code language-bash codeBlock_bY9V thin-scrollbar"><code class="codeBlockLines_e6Vv"><span class="token-line" style="color:#F8F8F2"><span class="token function" style="color:rgb(80, 250, 123)">git</span><span class="token plain"> commit -a -m </span><span class="token string" style="color:rgb(255, 121, 198)">"initial post 😸"</span><br></span></code></pre><div class="buttonGroup__atx"><button type="button" aria-label="Copy code to clipboard" title="Copy" class="clean-btn"><span class="copyButtonIcons_eSgA" aria-hidden="true"><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonIcon_y97N"><path fill="currentColor" d="M19,21H8V7H19M19,5H8A2,2 0 0,0 6,7V21A2,2 0 0,0 8,23H19A2,2 0 0,0 21,21V7A2,2 0 0,0 19,5M16,1H4A2,2 0 0,0 2,3V17H4V3H16V1Z"></path></svg><svg viewBox="0 0 24 24" class="copyButtonSuccessIcon_LjdS"><path fill="currentColor" d="M21,7L9,19L3.5,13.5L4.91,12.09L9,16.17L19.59,5.59L21,7Z"></path></svg></span></button></div></div></div><p>Bearz.sh is live.  A progressive launch for a documentation hub and blog around
automation, side projects, programming, self hosting, nerding 🤓 out on tech,
and working in the industry.</p><p>The docs section of the site will be around technology and drill into the
technical bits.  The blog is free form and not beholding to tech or clean
language, cause why the fuck not? There are tons of interesting topics
that are tagential to tech like relationships, family, and
company bullshit.</p><p>One of the greatest examples of bullshit you'll run into in technology aside from
scrum is this new wave to "bring your authentic selves to work" or radical
candor. Its a lie. Don't do it. Company actions completely contradict
this recent corporate theme.</p><p>Bring whatever you need to perform your work. Save your authentic self
and your best self for family and for you. If you have a dark sense of humor,
are too pragmatic, too direct, or even share views that are mainstream...
it will backfire and your authentic self will violate the company social media
and ethics policy.</p><p><img loading="lazy" src="https://media.giphy.com/media/Z1LYiyIPhnG9O/giphy.gif" alt="its a trap" class="img_ev3q"></p><p>Telling employees to bring their authentic self to work is  a great way for HR
to have the option to fire you later. What may be acceptible today will not be
in a few weeks or months. Be professional at all times and keep any views
unrelated to work outside of work.</p><p>The workforce today is filled with people that can't handle even the smallest
of confrontations or deal with slightly different views. The actions of most
companies contradict the whole concept of "bring your whole authethic self to
work" if you pay attention.</p><p>Companies are rolling out AI software that will scrub text for anything that the
program thinks may be offsenive and ironically will be offensive to someone
because what it generates is so fake, cringe, cultish, and reeks of elitism.</p><p>For example, blacklist has origins in Britian in the 1600s and was used
heavily by the British Government in WWI. Yet software
and people swapping out that term for deny list. If someone that I cared about
was bothered by that term with a legit reason, sure, I would use something else
but not some fuckery like "deny list".</p><p>"Deny list" and "allow list" are what cringy elitists are going to use to keep
out the low status plebs from their swanky lil clubs to low key insult everyone and
avoid bad PR at the same time.</p><p>Blocklist and Trustedlist are better altneratives and they would be used if
companies actually believed in authenticity.</p><p>It reminds of me of religious subcultures where true believers™️ develop their
own sub culture that includes specific terms that let others know you're part
of the believers crowd, except companies are now more extreme than most
religions and it lacks any real morality and shifting definitions of sin.</p><p>To get fired even faster; put your authentic self on social media.
Its hard to create a great social content without some kind of polarization
and earning die hard haters eager to starve your family and put you out of work.</p><p>If you want to do social, go anonymous or stick to a benign social media presence
such as linked in and github and adopt the golden rule.</p><p>If you are just starting out in your career or come from another part of the world
it is too easy to snared in these kind of corporate mixed signals and are left
in the cold because you did what you were told and now Bob has it out for your
team because your boss and team in their way of building their new kingdom.</p><p>This blog will be covering company bullshit like that along with tech so that
you can focus on the cool technology stuff or hard stuff that drives impact,
shipping product, and other things that actually matter.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Bearz</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/bearz-sh</uri>
        </author>
    </entry>
</feed>